This got the boat to edge and it was turned upside down in the water and now began to sink down to the bottom.
Water poured in everywhere and the panic looked into the crew that was locked up in its cabins at this time.
Why were they locked up?
Well, because the area they were on used to be regularly affected by pirates who rob and sometimes steal the ships.
It was a security measure so that they would not be injured or ended up hostage to the pirates.
Unfortunately, this security measure became their death.
But not for the boat's chef Harrison Olene, 29 years.
He was in the toilet when all this happened and suddenly feels how the boat turns.
He is thrown out from the toilet and around the different spaces in the boat while at the same time becomes darker and darker
After all, when we humans breathe in, we breathe in oxygen, but when we exhale, the lungs emit a gas called carbon dioxide.
Slowly but surely, the air bubble would be filled with more and more carbon dioxide and in the end Harrison would die from it.
The air bubble had enough volume to make the oxygen last for about 60 hours before he would start to suffer carbon dioxide poisoning.
However, this was not something he himself knew about at this time.
In total darkness, Harrison manages to tear off some wooden panels from the walls and finds a mattress that he could use to build a small platform that he could sit on.
And there he would be sitting.
Dressed in only their underwear in the cold sea water, without food or fresh water to drink and in a cold and wet room
With a slow but surely declining oxygen supply and in total darkness, Harrison seemed to survive not so great.
Hour after hour passed.
Every little sound scared him.
The diver had not expected anyone to survive and Harrison had almost given up hope of being saved.
Unfortunately, after Harrison spent almost 3 days at 30 meters depth, he could not only take him to the surface.
There is something called scuba diving, or even "pressure drop" that can occur in all people who are suddenly exposed to a pressure cut.
When you dive, the body's different tissues absorb nitrogen from the breathing air which is in proportion to the pressure in the environment.
This is no problem as long as you stay at the same depth or the same pressure, but the problem arises when the pressure is reduced too quickly.
The nitrogen inside the body then turns to a gaseous form and forms bubbles in the tissues and blood.
It can lead to loss of sensation, paralysis and even brain damage.
In the worst case, this leads to a coma and that the person dies.
Harrison had to spend about 2 and a half days in a decompression chamber to get used to his body at the pressure on the surface.
Harrison had no idea how long he had been down in the boat.
He guessed in 12 hours and was very surprised that he almost spent 3 days all by himself in total darkness.
Harrison is very grateful that he survived but is still plagued by nightmares.